Noureddine Laassari

 ♠ Agadir, Morooco
 ☑ contact@laassari.com
 ♠ laassari.com
 in laassari

C laassari

Summary ₋

Full-stack developer with 5+ years of experience. I enjoy building accessible and performant web experiences using the latest technologies and tools.

I love following features from concept to deployment and monitoring the usage after to see how it affects users.

- Good experience with remote communications
- Strive for clean code
- Pragmatic and understands business needs

Experience _____

Elevo, Full-stack Developer

- Take responsibility for key features from Idea to delivery
- Migrate front-end from Flow to Typescript
- introduce storybook and work on the design system
- Introduce Docker for Development
- Stack: React Typescript Redux Git Storybook Jest PostgreSQL Ruby on Rails - Heroku - Docker

Fluicity, Software Engineer

- · Migrated frontend from Ruby on Rails to React.
- · Built several design system components in Storybook
- 20% bundle size & load time improvement using various strategies.
- 10% increase of the accessibility score and reached 90% score on new pages.
- Lead the tech part of new main features and assisted during the product discovery phase
- E2E testing (Cypress) and unit tests (Jest) for key features.
- Stack: React Redux Git GitHub Actions Cypress Storybook Jest React-intl - Material-UI - PostgreSQL - Ruby on Rails - Heroku

Devinweb, Frontend Web Developer

- Built a gifting platform (resal.me) front-end while ensuring accessibility, speed, and SEO friendliness.
- Maintained a dashboard used by the partners of resal.me to update order statuses, notify users, cancel orders, and more using.
- Built and maintained an admin panel for an e-store with different features.
- Maintained a React Native application, added new features like Apple Pay and upgraded it to a newer version.
- Stack: Vue.js/Nuxt.js React React Native Axios Tailwindcss Moment Laravel

Paris (remote) Aug 2021 - Mar 2023

1 year 7 months

Paris (remote) Mar 2020 - July 2021 1 year 4 months

Tetouan, Morocco Nov 2018 - Jan 2020 1 year 2 months

Projects

Offliner ☑ Laassari/Offliner 🗹

- Developed a PWA where the user can download and manage Youtube videos through the app. The user can, also, create and manage playlists. The app supports background fetch and is registred as a share target.
- Tools Used: Typescript, React, Tailwindcss, Docker, Express

Focus Laassari/focus ☑

• Developed a chrome extension to help focus on work in intervals using the Pomodoro technique. You can customise the focus time, rest time and extended rest time. in addition to the websites you wish to block during Focus

• Tools Used: Javascript, chrome.extension API

Education _

University of Ibn Zohr, Physics

Sept 2013 – June 2016